Daniel Nucci . Jarvis Consulting

I am a graduate of Ontario Tech University obtaining a degree in Software Engineering with an IoT specialization. I found a passion for software development in high school when I joined a robotics team. I see software and information technology as tools in an engineer's/developer's toolbox. The language that I am most proficient in is Java which I have used for more than 8 years. Java also is the language through which I learned about data structures, OOP, version control tools, and workflow methodologies (such as Agile, Scrum, Waterfall, and XP). Other languages I have learned include Bash, SQL (Postgres, mySQL, SQLite), Python, C (C#, C++, C), and Javascript. All of these tools have helped me develop my mindset surrounding software and problems at large. Since 2016, I have spent my summers as a STEM Instructor. Teaching students at multiple education levels has given me insight into summarizing data at multiple complexity levels. With this being said, I feel my skills in the software field can bring great value to companies seeking a developer that possesses a passion for solving problems with software.

Skills

Proficient: Java, Linux, Bash, RDBMS, SQL (mySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite), Agile, Scrum, Git, Android Development, XML / JSON / YAML

Competent: Python, Docker, Kubernetes, C# (.NET, Unity), Javascript / Typescript, C / C++, MongoDB, XP (Extreme Programming)

Familiar: Angular / Vue.js, Express.js, Node.js, QEMU, Kotlin, Perl, PHP

Jarvis Projects

Project source code: https://github.com/jarviscanada/jarvis_data_eng_DanielNucci

Linux Cluster Monitor Agent [GitHub]: Implemented a usage data collecting system that collates data from nodes in a Linux Cluster. This project was programmed using PostgreSQL (PSQL), Bash, crontab, docker, and a Google Compute Engine. The PSQL instance was hosted on a docker container on one of the nodes in the cluster. This database instance held device information about each node in the cluster on one table and the usage data associated with those nodes in another table. A Bash script run using a cron job by way of crontab is used to insert values into the aforementioned usage table. The Google Compute Engine instance was used to emulate the CentOS 7 operating system to ensure that the system was compatible with RHEL and CentOS.

Core Java Applications [GitHub]:

Grep App: In Progress JDBC App: In Progress

Highlighted Projects

Touchless Mall Kiosk System: Integrating 3 touchless technologies to create a mall kiosk that prevents the spread of SARS-CoV-2. The kiosk was fabricated to communicate to other kiosks to direct mall shoppers to their destination. I managed a 4-person team and organized workflow with a Gantt chart and assigned tasks to each member.

Text-Based Connect Four [GitHub]: The game of Connect 4 put into a Client-Server Java program hosted in the terminal. A queuing system was programmed to automatically pair two clients of opposite colours together to play a match of Connect Four.

ROPE (Rapid Online Program Evaluator): Produced for coders to speed up their programming prowess by challenging them to code programs. Leveraging Kubernetes and Docker, the website was automatically load balanced to accommodate needs. Users were encouraged to make accounts that are linked to their progress.

Professional Experiences

Software Developer, Jarvis (01/2022-present): Developed a wide variety of applications using Java, SQL, and Bash. All projects were developed using an Agile and Scrum development environment with a two-week sprint length. Other tools such as Docker, Maven, Cron Jobs, git, and more were used to solve problems set by each project.

Engineering Outreach Instructor, Ontario Tech University (05/2019-08/2019): Taught electrical engineering curriculum at multiple education levels to high school classrooms of 25+. Tutored students on subjects ranging from the

power grid to breadboard electronics / basic circuits. Developed and implemented engineering curriculum for 6 groups of high school students. Instructed campers on topics such as computer science, physics, engineering, chemistry, and forensics.

STEM Camp Counselor, W.A.F.F.L.E.S. Community Robotics (06/2016-08/2017): Guided 5+ FIRST robotics Lego League Jr. teams that contained a handful of children aged 7 - 14. Trained campers in Mindstorm robotics education, and 21st-century skills. Assisted campers with presenting a solution to an environmental problem.

IT Technician, Toronto District School Board (06/2015-08/2015): Travelled between 20+ schools in the TDSB and troubleshot issues that were encountered. Installed networking equipment, setup printers, upgraded and reformatted hundreds of Windows machines. Used command line tools to set up 25+ network switches for a hot-swap in a pre-existing network.

Education

Ontario Tech University (2017-2021), Bachelor's of Software Engineering with IoT Specialization, Faculty of Engineering and Applied Science - President's list (2020) - Dean's list (2021)

Miscellaneous

- Achieved top 25% in the CCC (Canada Computing Competition) Senior Division (2017)
- Volunteered as a Control Systems Advisor, Robot Inspector, and many other roles for robotics tournaments
- Mentored students in software development on a FIRST Robotics team
- Hybrid Athletics (Running, Cycling, Weight Training)